Chapter 4 Governance in the words of the
Bletchley
Declaration, substantial risks may arise
from potential intentional misuse
or unintended issues of control relating
to alignment with
human intent. These issues are in part
because those
capabilities are not fully understood.
There is potential for
serious, even catastrophic harm, either
deliberate or unintentional, stemming
from the most significant capabilities of
these AI models.
Artificial intelligence has the potential
to revolutionize numerous aspects
of society, from healthcare to
transportation to scientific research.
Through the previous chapters you have
seen AI's ability
to defeat world champions at go, generate
photorealistic images
from text descriptions, and even discover
new antibiotics. However,
these developments also raise significant
challenges and risks, including
job displacement, privacy infringements,
and the potential for AI
systems to make consequential mistakes or
be misused. See
the Chapter 2 on Risks for the Full
Spectrum
Technical AI safety research is necessary
to ensure AI
behaves reliably and aligns with human
values, especially as
it becomes more capable and autonomous.
Even though technical
research is necessary, it alone is not
sufficient to
address the full spectrum of challenges
posed by advanced
AI systems. The scope of AI governance is
broad,
so this chapter will primarily focus on
large scale
risks associated with Frontier AI. As a
reminder, Frontier
AIs are highly capable models that could
possess dangerous
capabilities sufficient to pose severe
risks to public safety.
Although in recent history many state of
the art
advancements have been driven by LLMs or
foundation models,
frontier AI as a term is not limited to
just these types of models. We will
examine why
governance is necessary, how it
complements technical AI safety
efforts, and the key challenges and
opportunities in this
rapidly evolving field. We will focus on
the governance
of commercial and civil AI applications.
As military AI
governance involves a distinctive There is
figure 4.1 in
the textbook. Here it depicts
distinguishing AI models according
to their level of potential harm and
generality. We
focus here on frontier AI models.